[
    {
      "question": "What do you call the meal you eat on New Year's Day?",
      "options": [
        "orizume",
        "jūbako ryōri",
        "shōjin ryōri",
        "osechi ryōri"
      ],
      "answer": "osechi ryōri"
    },
    {
      "question": "What do you call the soup with mochi rice cakes that you eat on New Year's Day?",
      "options": [
        "ozōni",
        "oshiruko",
        "botamochi",
        "agemochi"
      ],
      "answer": "ozōni"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is mochi made of?",
      "options": [
        "rice",
        "potato",
        "soybeans",
        "wheat"
      ],
      "answer": "rice"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is soy sauce made of?",
      "options": [
        "meat",
        "fish",
        "rice",
        "soybeans"
      ],
      "answer": "soybeans"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is miso made of?",
      "options": [
        "meat",
        "fish",
        "rice",
        "soybeans"
      ],
      "answer": "soybeans"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are takuan pickles made of?",
      "options": [
        "lemon",
        "apple",
        "daikon raddish",
        "cucumber"
      ],
      "answer": "daikon raddish"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is kamaboko made of?",
      "options": [
        "rice",
        "fish",
        "milk",
        "soybeans"
      ],
      "answer": "fish"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the word agari that you hear in a sushi restaurant refer to?",
      "options": [
        "tea",
        "miso soup",
        "ginger",
        "soy sauce"
      ],
      "answer": "tea"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the word murasaki that you hear in a sushi restaurant refer to?",
      "options": [
        "salt",
        "miso",
        "soy sauce",
        "ginger"
      ],
      "answer": "soy sauce"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which vegetable is in kappa-maki sushi?",
      "options": [
        "cucumber",
        "carrot",
        "Daikon raddish",
        "avocado"
      ],
      "answer": "cucumber"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is in tekka-maki sushi?",
      "options": [
        "tuna",
        "pickles",
        "cucumber",
        "nattō"
      ],
      "answer": "tuna"
    },
    {
      "question": "When you have sushi, which fish does the word toro usually refer to?",
      "options": [
        "sea bream",
        "salmon",
        "tuna",
        "eel"
      ],
      "answer": "tuna"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the sushi that has uni sea urchin or ikura salmon roe on top of a bite-sized portion of rice and is wrapped with nori seaweed?",
      "options": [
        "shiro-maki [castle roll]",
        "gunkan-maki [warship roll]",
        "taiko-maki [drum roll]",
        "taihō-maki [cannon roll]"
      ],
      "answer": "gunkan-maki [warship roll]"
    },
    {
      "question": "What do you call the negi green onion or wasabi horseradish that are served with soba noodles?",
      "options": [
        "yakumi",
        "tenkabutsu",
        "otōshi",
        "tsukemono"
      ],
      "answer": "yakumi"
    },
    {
      "question": "The hot water used for cooking soba noodles is mixed with tsuyu dipping sauce to make a tasty broth, which you drink after you finish eating soba. What do you call this water?",
      "options": [
        "sobajiru",
        "sobamizu",
        "sobacha",
        "sobayu"
      ],
      "answer": "sobayu"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does kitsune [fox] udon noodles contain as one of its ingredients?",
      "options": [
        "chicken meat",
        "fox meat",
        "steamed fish paste",
        "deep-fried thin tofu"
      ],
      "answer": "deep-fried thin tofu"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are udon noodles with mochi called?",
      "options": [
        "chikara udon",
        "shiro udon",
        "sumō udon",
        "kagami udon"
      ],
      "answer": "chikara udon"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which area of Japan is the home of Sanuki udon?",
      "options": [
        "Nagasaki Prefecture",
        "Kagawa Prefecture",
        "Ibaraki Prefecture",
        "Akita Prefecture"
      ],
      "answer": "Kagawa Prefecture"
    },
    {
      "question": "What other expression is used to describe ramen noodles?",
      "options": [
        "chūka udon",
        "chūgoku soba",
        "chūka soba",
        "chūgoku udon"
      ],
      "answer": "chūka soba"
    },
    {
      "question": "What do you call ramen noodles that use soup made from pork bones?",
      "options": [
        "tonjiru ramen",
        "butabara ramen",
        "tonkotsu ramen",
        "butabone ramen"
      ],
      "answer": "tonkotsu ramen"
    },
    {
      "question": "In Japan, what do people eat on December 31st?",
      "options": [
        "soba [buckwheat noodle]",
        "mochi [rice cake]",
        "sushi",
        "okayu [rice porridge]"
      ],
      "answer": "soba [buckwheat noodle]"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the two main ingredients of oyako-don [parent and child bowl]?",
      "options": [
        "mutton and lamb meat",
        "chicken and egg",
        "tuna and steamed fish paste",
        "carrot and daikon radish"
      ],
      "answer": "chicken and egg"
    },
    {
      "question": "In Japan, what do people eat on Doyō no Ushi no Hi [Day of the Ox in midsummer]?",
      "options": [
        "eel",
        "beef",
        "soba noodles",
        "watermelon"
      ],
      "answer": "eel"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which sweets do people eat on Kodomo no Hi [Children's Day] on May 5th?",
      "options": [
        "kusa mochi",
        "mame mochi",
        "kashiwa mochi",
        "sakura mochi"
      ],
      "answer": "kashiwa mochi"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the box lunch called that has white rice with a umeboshi pickled plum in the center?",
      "options": [
        "hinomaru bentō [rising sun box lunch]",
        "nihon bentō [Japan box lunch]",
        "hata bentō [flag box lunch]",
        "kōhaku bentō [red and white box lunch]"
      ],
      "answer": "hinomaru bentō [rising sun box lunch]"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the box lunch called that has white rice with a variety of side dishes?",
      "options": [
        "yamanouchi bentō",
        "makunouchi bentō",
        "dohyōnouchi bentō",
        "hananouchi bentō"
      ],
      "answer": "makunouchi bentō"
    },
    {
      "question": "What do you put on your hands when you make onigiri rice balls?",
      "options": [
        "salt",
        "sugar",
        "pepper",
        "sesame oil"
      ],
      "answer": "salt"
    },
    {
      "question": "What do you call the glutinous rice cooked with azuki beans that you eat on festive occasions?",
      "options": [
        "kokuhan",
        "chahan",
        "sekihan",
        "ryokuhan"
      ],
      "answer": "sekihan"
    },
    {
      "question": "What do you call the dish that you dip thinly sliced meat in boiling water for a few seconds before you eat?",
      "options": [
        "basha basha",
        "bushu bushu",
        "shobo shobo",
        "shabu shabu"
      ],
      "answer": "shabu shabu"
    },
    {
      "question": "When you eat sukiyaki, in what do you dip it before you eat?",
      "options": [
        "vinegar",
        "milk",
        "miso",
        "raw egg"
      ],
      "answer": "raw egg"
    },
    {
      "question": "What do you call the kind of tempura in which several ingredients such as onions and shrimp are fried together?",
      "options": [
        "maruage",
        "kakiage",
        "yoseage",
        "matomeage"
      ],
      "answer": "kakiage"
    },
      {
      "question": "What is in Ishikari-nabe hot pot that is the specialty of Hokkaido?",
      "options": [
        "squid",
        "crab",
        "sea urchin",
        "salmon"
      ],
      "answer": "salmon"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the Tokyo specialty dish of flour-based batter with vegetables that is cooked on a hot plate?",
      "options": [
        "modanyaki",
        "okonomiyaki",
        "monjayaki",
        "karumeyaki"
      ],
      "answer": "monjayaki"
    },
    {
      "question": "In Nagoya, what do you put on tonkatsu pork cutlets instead of tonkatsu sauce?",
      "options": [
        "miso sause",
        "soy sauce",
        "ketchup sause",
        "mayonnaise sause"
      ],
      "answer": "miso sause"
    },
    {
      "question": "What do you call the Nagoya specialty dish that features small pieces of grilled eel on white rice?",
      "options": [
        "himatsubushi",
        "hitsumabushi",
        "hitsubumashi",
        "himabutsushi"
      ],
      "answer": "hitsumabushi"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the term used in Osaka for Osaka-style specialties such as okonomiyaki savory pancakes and takoyaki octopus balls?",
      "options": [
        "konamon",
        "shirumon",
        "yakimon",
        "sōsumon"
      ],
      "answer": "konamon"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the manufacturer of the sauce that is usually used for Hiroshima-style okonomiyaki savory pancakes?",
      "options": [
        "Oni Sauce",
        "Kappa Sauce",
        "Tengu Sauce",
        "Otafuku Sauce"
      ],
      "answer": "Otafuku Sauce"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the Akita Prefecture specialty food of pounded rice wrapped around a skewer and grilled over a hearth?",
      "options": [
        "damatanpo",
        "kiridango",
        "kiritanpo",
        "damadango"
      ],
      "answer": "kiritanpo"
    },
    {
      "question": "What do you call the dish that is originally from Hokkaido and is mutton grilled on a griddle?",
      "options": [
        "Caesar",
        "Genghis Khan",
        "Napoleon",
        "Alexander"
      ],
      "answer": "Genghis Khan"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is the famous ekiben [box lunch sold at train stations] of Hokkaido?",
      "options": [
        "ika meshi [squid rice]",
        "asari meshi [short-necked clam rice]",
        "maguro meshi [tuna rice]",
        "hirame meshi [flounder rice]"
      ],
      "answer": "ika meshi [squid rice]"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the food made from soymilk for which Kyoto and Nikko famous?",
      "options": [
        "yuba",
        "nattō",
        "hanpen",
        "aburaage"
      ],
      "answer": "yuba"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which town is famous for producing nattō fermented soybeans?",
      "options": [
        "Takasaki",
        "Mito",
        "Kumamoto",
        "Kitakata"
      ],
      "answer": "Mito"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which town is famous for producing eel?",
      "options": [
        "Hamamatsu",
        "Hakodate",
        "Sendai",
        "Hukuoka"
      ],
      "answer": "Hamamatsu"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which dish is not Okinawan cuisine?",
      "options": [
        "rafutē",
        "mentaiko",
        "gōya chanpurū",
        "taco rice"
      ],
      "answer": "mentaiko"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following foods did not exist during the Edo period?",
      "options": [
        "sushi",
        "tempura",
        "gyūdon",
        "gyūdon"
      ],
      "answer": "gyūdon"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not a food associated with autumn in Japan?",
      "options": [
        "strawberries",
        "mushrooms",
        "chestnuts",
        "pears"
      ],
      "answer": "strawberries"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the fish and vegetable Hokkaido specialty that is cooked on a teppan (Japanese griddle)?",
      "options": [
        "Tonton'yaki",
        "Dondon'yaki",
        "Janjan'yaki",
        "Chanchan'yaki"
      ],
      "answer": "Chanchan'yaki"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the pork and egg Kansai specialty that is cooked on a teppan (Japanese griddle)?",
      "options": [
        "Sanpēyaki",
        "Tonpēyaki",
        "Shunpēyaki",
        "Konpēyaki"
      ],
      "answer": "Tonpēyaki"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the traditional home cooking in Kyoto called?",
      "options": [
        "obanzai",
        "omanzai",
        "obonzai",
        "omonzai"
      ],
      "answer": "obanzai"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is the characteristic sause for Chicken Nanban?",
      "options": [
        "salsa",
        "tartar sauce",
        "Worcester sauce",
        "meat sauce"
      ],
      "answer": "tartar sauce"
    },
    {
      "question": "What do you call a box lunch decorated to look like an animal or a character in anime?",
      "options": [
        "Kyaraben",
        "Aniben",
        "Dezaben",
        "Noriben"
      ],
      "answer": "Kyaraben"
    },
    {
      "question": "What kind of meat is used in Sakura Nabe (Hotpot)?",
      "options": [
        "mutton",
        "frong meat",
        "horsemeat",
        "goat meat"
      ],
      "answer": "horsemeat"
    },
    {
      "question": "What kind of meat is used in Botan Nabe (Peony Hotpot)?",
      "options": [
        "venison",
        "wild boar meat",
        "bear meat",
        "rabbit meat"
      ],
      "answer": "wild boar meat"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the specialty of Nagasaki that consists of spaghetti and a deep-fried pork cutlet over a bed of rice with demiglace sauce?",
      "options": [
        "Toruko Raisu (Turkey Rice)",
        "Ejiputo Raisu（Egypt Rice)",
        "Monako Raisu (Monaco Rice)",
        "Kenia Raisu (Kenya Rice)"
      ],
      "answer": "Toruko Raisu (Turkey Rice)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a speciality seaweed from Okinawa?",
      "options": [
        "umi ichigo (sea strawberry)",
        "umi ringo (sea apple)",
        "umi suika (sea watermelon)",
        "umi budō (sea grape)"
      ],
      "answer": "umi budō (sea grape)"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the specialized cuisine that uses no meat served in Buddhist temples?",
      "options": [
        "bukkyō ryōri",
        "shōjin ryōri",
        "binbō ryōri",
        "yasai ryōri"
      ],
      "answer": "shōjin ryōri"
    }
  ]
  